Matlock. M-A-T-L-O-C-K.
Right. No, just one night.
Oh, good. Okay, well, we'll
be there in about an hour,
if the traffic's not too bad.
Thanks a lot. Bye.
Good news, Dad. The Wilmont
had a two-room suite available.
This way, we can go to the
wedding and then the reception,
and we don't have to worry
about driving home late at night.
We'll just take the
elevator right upstairs.
Dad?
Ooh, I just feel awful.
- What's wrong?
- Oh, I just feel awful.
What? Do you have a stomachache?
Oh, I bet Billy put gunpowder
in those corn cakes last night.
Oh, I don't think
you'd better go.
I guess I can go by myself.
Oh, I'll feel better
once I get there.
Well, can I do anything?
You can torch Billy's house.
How you doing, Dad?
Oh, I don't know
why I drink this junk.
Doesn't make me feel good.
All it does is make me burp,
leave white stuff on the mouth.
I can't hear you.
Now I...
Now I know I'm sick.
There's a fellow down
there barbecuing hot dogs,
and the thought of eating one
of them makes me wanna gag.
What'd you say?
I said, there's a fell...
- Never mind.
- How you doing?
Oh, well, you're hot.
Maybe you shouldn't
go down there.
They'll be disappointed.
Well, they'll get over it.
Tell Tim and Shannon I'll
come down later, if I feel better.
Ha, ha, ha. Okay.
Come on, sit down. Come on.
Here's the remote. Why
don't you watch a little TV
and I'll come check
on you in a little while?
- I love you, Pop.
- Bye.
Heh. Feel better.
Bye.
It's in the cup.
Strong finish for Larry Mize
on this difficult third round.
Now, the 14th. That
could go on the 14th.
Mark McCumber setting up his
third shot at 100, 1 10 yards out.
Hi, Dad.
How you feeling?
Like I swallowed a lemon.
But you'll never believe what I
saw through the window just now.
This man was trying
to kiss this woman
in the house across
the street there.
She slapped him.
I don't think it
was her husband.
After all these years, I finally
find out my dad's a peeper.
I wasn't peeping,
I was just looking.
I spoke to Dr. Caswell.
He prescribed some
medication for your stomach.
Peeping!
I'm sorry.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Okay. Well, shall
we call it a night?
- I'm not tired.
- Well, I am.
I'll see you in the morning.
How about a hand of gin?
Oh, not tonight,
Dad, I've really had it.
Just one?
Okay.
But you have to promise
not to yell and throw
your cards if you lose.
One time I threw my cards.
Just one time.
I'm not gonna lose.
Hmph.
Six, six, seven,
seven, eight, eight...
nine, nine, ten, ten.
So how was the party?
- Well, young love.
- Mm.
It's very romantic, that's
why I came upstairs early.
- I was getting depressed.
- Mm.
You collecting jacks?
Maybe.
That's a lot of points if
you get stuck with them.
Thanks for the tip, Dad.
You need all my discards?
No. Just that one.
Gin.
You can't gin that fast.
Well, now, you can't
accuse me of cheating, Dad.
You're the one that dealt.
- Well, you just took three cards.
- I had a good hand.
Three cards, and you gin.
Wait. Wait a second. How many
points did you have in that hand?
- A lot.
- Dad.
- We'll go again.
- No.
- No. No.
- We'll go again.
- No.
Go again.
One, one, two,
two, three, three...
Oh.
Follow me around back.
- Yes, sir.
What in the world is
going on down there?
I don't know.
But that's the house I was
telling you about last night
where I saw that fight.
Looks like the
medical examiner's car.
Yeah. It does.
I'm going down there.
Oh, Dad.
And so you were acquainted
with the deceased, were you?
Yeah. About a year I think.
Who died?
Helaine Cameron.
- Did she live here?
- Yeah.
Oh.
Dark hair? Mid 30s?
Yeah.
The police say she
was stabbed in the back.
Dad.
I think that's her husband.
He's being arrested.
That's not the man I saw
fighting with her last night.
- It's not?
- No.
I think they got the wrong guy.
Dad. Dad.
This isn't your case.
You're not involved.
We go back to the hotel now?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
Um...
Let's stop by the district
attorney's office first.
Yeah.
I think you've arrested
the wrong man.
I find that very
hard to believe.
I was there, across
the street, in the hotel.
I could see into the house.
Somebody else was inside
by the time this Cameron
fellow came home.
Could you identify
this individual?
No. No.
By the time Mr. Cameron
arrived, the house was dark.
But somebody else was there.
Mr. Matlock, are you aware
of the evidence against...
Can I just finish?
Of course.
Earlier in the evening,
when the lights were
still on, and I could see,
I saw the dead woman,
when she was still alive,
fighting with another man.
She slapped him. He
slapped her up against the wall.
Are you done?
Yes.
Mr. Matlock,
you know that I respect
you and your reputation.
But the evidence here is simple,
and in my estimation, it's conclusive.
The murder weapon
was a kitchen knife
with prints on it from two people,
the victim and her husband.
No one else.
Two months ago,
Philip Cameron took out
a half-million-dollar life
insurance policy on his wife
and, most damning of all,
she was having an affair,
and he knew about it.
Somebody ran out of the
house, just as he got home.
Mr. Matlock, I wish more
people would come forward
and get involved the
way you have today.
But the evidence
here is overwhelming.
It's a slam-dunk
case. Murder one.
Murder's not a basketball game.
Well, thank you for coming by.
- Jerk.
- Yeah.
Come on, Dad, let's go home.
- He didn't even listen to me.
- You did the best you could.
Let's go see Philip Cameron.
- Why?
- I want to talk to him.
Dad, you're a potential
witness in this case.
You can't represent him.
No. But you can.
Did you tell the DA you
saw someone in the house?
Yeah. But he's gonna
prosecute anyway.
I don't understand.
He thinks he's
got a strong case.
What is happening to me?
Helaine and I had this simple,
good life down in Porterville,
and nothing has gone
right since we came here.
- Is that where you're from, Porterville?
- Yeah.
I didn't kill
Helaine. I loved her.
Truth is, she was
having an affair.
And I was mad. But I
was trying to get her back.
DA's gonna say you were
so angry about the affair
you killed her in order to
collect the insurance money.
No. I never took any
insurance out on her.
There was a half-million-dollar
policy on her life.
No. I didn't do that.
- No?
- No.
Why don't you tell us
what happened that night?
The night Helaine died,
we had dinner together.
You barbecued some hot dogs.
What are you, some
kind of Peeping Tom?
I wasn't peeping.
I just saw you fixed hot
dogs. For heaven's sakes.
Go on.
Over dinner, we decided to
give our marriage another go.
She was gonna break it off
with her boyfriend that evening,
which is why I went
to the office for...
I don't know how long.
So that they could be alone.
What did this fellow look like?
Six-two, slender, brown hair.
Actor. Wayne Drummond.
Sounds like the fella I saw
fighting with her that night.
Thinks he's God's gift to women.
Maybe he doesn't
like being rejected.
Maybe he took out the insurance,
killed her, and framed
you for the murder.
Why would he do that?
I don't know.
Wanna try and find out?
Let me translate that for you.
My father's asking me
if I wanna represent you.
Question is, do you
want me to represent you?
You bet.
- Found your wife in the kitchen?
- Yes.
- Did you touch the knife?
- No.
What floor were you on?
Two.
You saw everything? - Yeah.
Do you mind my asking what you
were doing peeping into this house?
I wasn't peeping.
I didn't feel well. I was bored,
and I looked out the window.
I wasn't peeping. Peeping.
When this is over, I'm
gonna sell this place.
Until then, I suggest
you get some blinds.
Daggone.
What is it, Dad?
Hey! Hey!
TRI2L9.
That is your license
plate number.
- Isn't it, Miss Garber?
- What?
I say that's your license
plate number, isn't it?
- Who are you?
- Ben Matlock.
Your car was parked outside
Philip Cameron's house
the night his wife was murdered.
It wasn't my car.
It was there again this morning. I
saw it. That's how I remembered.
I think you're mistaken.
As sure as that cute
little nose is on your face,
your car was there,
and I'd like to know why.
Am I under some
kind of legal obligation
to answer these questions?
No.
Then why don't
you just buzz off?
Okay. But you should
know, in open court,
they'll hold you in
contempt if you don't answer.
Who said anything about court?
Me. See you.
Wait a minute. Where you going?
- I'm buzzing off.
- Wait.
Wait.
This is really embarrassing.
My boyfriend was having an
affair with Helaine Cameron.
I followed him there.
I was so angry
that I wanted to go in
there and do something.
I don't know what.
Then I came to my
senses, and I went home.
- For the night?
- Huh?
By yourself?
Your boyfriend didn't come?
Uh-uh.
- His name Wayne?
- Yeah.
How did you know that?
Everybody knows that.
- I don't wanna play gin, dad.
- Seven...
seven, eight, eight,
nine, nine, ten, ten.
Dad, it just upsets you.
Did I throw my
cards the other night?
No. But you didn't talk to
me for an hour and a half.
I didn't feel good. I
had a stomachache.
I feel better now. Come on.
Your little winning streak
of seven straight hands
is about to come to an end.
- Nine. Nine straight hands.
- Oh.
Pick a card.
Ho, ho. Ho-ho-ho.
That's gonna fill a
nice little hole right here.
Okay. Now, isn't this fun?
- It's a joy, Dad.
- Mm-hm.
Ah.
Something tells me
you need this little card.
No.
You don't need this little card.
Gin.
You looking mighty pretty.
Why don't you get
out of here? I mean...
- Unh.
- Isn't that what you want?
I frighten you,
and you like that.
- You revolt me.
- You were staring at me.
You think about me when you get into
bed with that sweet husband of yours?
I liked that. You
like to play rough.
Wayne, try to keep it sexy.
Dad.
- They were rehearsing that scene.
- Yeah.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me, Mr. Drummond.
Hello. My name
is Leanne Mclntyre.
I'm representing Philip
Cameron in the murder trial.
I was wondering if I could
ask you a couple of questions.
Take five.
Thank you.
Mr. Drummond, I'd like you to
meet my father, Ben Matlock.
- Hi.
- I saw you
at Helaine Cameron's
house the night she died.
Were you working on this scene?
Yeah. That's her understudy.
I guess that's what made it
look like you were fighting.
This scene.
How much did you see?
Did Helaine break
up with you that night?
- No.
- Did she tell you
she was never
gonna see you again?
We were making plans to
spend the weekend together
when her husband
went out of town.
Who told you she
was going to end it?
Her husband? Is
that what he said?
He said that he and Helaine
were gonna put their
marriage back together.
That's a lie.
I loved Helaine
and she loved me.
She was alive when I left.
Very much alive.
Well, we've taken up
enough of your time.
Thanks very much.
You know, there's
another way to look at this.
Maybe Helaine asked
him for a divorce.
Maybe that's why he killed her.
Maybe I misunderstood
everything I saw.
So, what do you think?
He grabbed her and tried
to kiss her, she slapped him,
then he went for her
and grabbed her again.
That's just what
happened in the play.
So where does that leave us?
Someone was in the house
when Philip Cameron came home.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
That's all we need.
Miss Galloway,
how long have you lived next
door to Philip and Helaine Cameron?
Four years, ever
since they moved in.
Did they seem like they
were happily married?
Objection, Your Honor.
No foundation. Calls
for a speculation.
I'll rephrase.
Miss Galloway, in
the last six months,
did you witness any fights between
Philip and Helaine Cameron?
Oh, yes, I have.
And were you aware what
they were fighting about?
It was very clear.
Mr. Cameron was very angry.
He told his wife that she would
have to stop seeing another man.
He told her that she was
destroying their marriage,
and he wouldn't stand for it.
You say he was very
upset and very angry?
Very.
Thank you.
So Chinese, Italian, what
do you feel like tonight?
Wayne, listen,
a lawyer named Ben Matlock
came in to see me yesterday.
What's he want with you?
He saw me outside
the Camerons' house
the night that Helaine
Cameron was murdered.
You were outside the house?
What were you doing there?
I followed you there.
I knew about you and Helaine.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
Wayne, you know I love you,
and I don't wanna lose you.
But if you're gonna
carry on like this,
then I think that we should
just end it here, right now,
before things get any worse.
I'd really like to try and
make this up to you.
Hey.
When we got to
the Cameron house,
Philip Cameron said he
just got home from work,
found his wife dead.
We did a thorough
examination of the crime scene.
Hmm.
Did you find the murder
weapon, detective?
Yes, sir. It was a
6-inch carving knife.
Did you find any
fingerprints on the knife?
Yes, sir, we did.
By the morning, we were able
to establish two sets of prints.
The victim's, Helaine Cameron,
and the defendant, Philip Cameron.
It was at that time that we
placed Mr. Cameron under arrest.
Thank you. Nothing further.
Miss Mclntyre.
Yes, Your Honor.
Detective Cavallo, did
you tell Mr. Cameron
that his fingerprints
were on the knife?
- Yes, I did.
- What did he say?
He said that it was the
only sharp knife in the house,
and that he used it to carve
three or four times a week.
Thank you.
Mr. Wygot.
The state rests, Your Honor.
Is the defense ready?
Yes, we are, Your Honor,
and for my first witness,
I would like to call
Mr. Benjamin Matlock.
Conrad? CONRAD: Yo.
- You following Karen?
- Yeah.
Right now she's outside the
Cameron house, sitting in her car.
What's she doing in her car?
I give up.
I just followed her here.
First, she was with
Wayne at the bar.
Then she came here.
And right now, all she's
doing is sitting in her car,
watching the house.
- Anybody in there?
- Uh, nope.
Dad. Come on.
Come on.
Conrad, stay on her. I gotta go.
Okay.
Mr. Matlock, where were you on
the night of Saturday, March 18th?
- The Wilmont Hotel.
- Situated where?
3231 Oleander Drive.
That's right across the street
from 3230 Oleander Drive,
- the Camerons' house.
- That's right.
That night, did you have a clear
view of the Camerons' house
from your hotel window?
Yes. I could see
directly into the den.
At around midnight, did you
see Mr. Cameron coming home?
Yes. I saw Mr. Cameron
drive his car up to his garage.
At that time, did you
see anything else?
Yeah. The minute he
slammed his car door,
I saw a shadowy
figure run from the den
and out the side of the garage.
Let me make sure
I understand you.
You're saying that someone
else was in the house
when Mr. Cameron returned home.
I'm certain of it.
Thank you, Mr. Matlock.
What brought you to the
Wilmont Hotel, Mr. Matlock?
Fellow I know is
getting married.
How was the wedding?
- I, uh, I didn't go.
- Why not?
I wasn't feeling well.
Well, you must have
been feeling pretty sick
to drive all the way
from Willow Springs
- then decide not to go to the wedding.
- It was just a little stomachache.
Did you take any medication
for this little stomachache?
The doctor prescribed something.
Something that
required a prescription.
Was there any narcotic in it,
something to help you sleep?
Um...
Maybe.
How far away do you think your
window at the Wilmont Hotel was
from the Camerons' house?
I don't know.
Please, your best guess.
Um...
Forty, 50 yards.
And while you were
peeping from this window,
you saw this shadowy figure.
- I wasn't peeping.
- Objection, Your Honor.
Sustained. Mr. Wygot.
The very idea! Peeping.
Mr. Matlock.
- Your Honor, you know me.
- Dad.
He said I was peeping.
How dare you!
May I continue?
- Go ahead.
- Peeping.
Mr. Matlock, are you sure
you saw the shadowy figure?
Yes.
Was he tall, short,
fat, thin, black,
white, man or woman?
You're not really sure
who or even what you saw.
- Are you, Mr. Matlock?
- I saw somebody.
Let's be perfectly clear
about what happened on
Saturday night, March the 18th.
It was dark outside
and the lights were off
in the Camerons' house.
You were at least 40 yards away,
taking narcotics, which,
according to the prescription,
would have affected
your perceptions,
and still you want us to believe
that you saw this shadowy figure
come running out of the
back of the Camerons' house.
Are you sure it wasn't
just a shadow, Mr. Matlock,
that given the darkness
and your drugged state,
you weren't just
imagining things?
I saw somebody!
Sure.
Nothing further, Your Honor.
And I wasn't peeping.
Hi.
Why don't we do it the easy way?
What's in the mail?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You fight with mailmen
on a daily basis?
Why don't we just take a look?
No! CONRAD: Thank you.
- Give me that.
- No, no, no.
"Dear Helaine, I thought
writing you would be better
than showing up on your doorstep
or possibly doing
something I would regret.
Wayne will never love
you the way he loves me.
He will use you as
he used other women,
but will always come back to me.
Karen."
What did you think you
would do that you might regret?
I wrote her a letter.
She was... sleeping
with my boyfriend.
- Your boyfriend?
- Yes.
I thought... Hmm.
I didn't kill her.
Well, you weren't
at home either.
I was sleeping. How
would you know anyway?
As luck would have it,
the smoke alarms
went off in your building.
All of the apartments
were evacuated.
You weren't there.
I told you, I didn't kill her.
Then where were you?
All right.
I have another job at night.
I answer calls on a 900 number.
What kind of calls?
Talking to lonely men.
Sex on the telephone?
Yeah.
So when I was driving away
that night, that's where I went.
I was there till about
3 in the morning.
Maybe you're just gonna have to
pin this murder on somebody else.
You ever call one of
those 900 sex numbers?
No.
Too expensive?
I don't wanna call somebody
to have them talk dirty to me.
Yeah, too expensive. I
went over there today.
You should see some of
those women answering phones.
What women answering phones?
I was just telling Ben I
checked Karen Garber's alibi.
She was answering
phones that night.
Hmm.
I get this kind of bad feeling.
If Karen didn't kill
Helaine Cameron...
- Don't even say it, Dad.
- Say what?
Philip may have lied.
Maybe his wife was
gonna leave him.
- You said it anyway.
- Hm.
Here.
- Hmm.
- What?
Mr. Drummond, you're
currently rehearsing for a play
at the Actors Repertory
Theater. Is that correct?
Yes, I am.
Is that where you
met Helaine Cameron?
Yes. She was cast opposite me.
How would you characterize
your relationship with her?
Was it professional?
Yes.
- At first.
- And then what happened?
We fell in love.
Did you know that
she was married?
Yes. I regret that
she was married.
But these things happen.
We rehearsed together all
day, sometimes at night, and...
What can I say?
We fell in love.
We hadn't planned on it.
Love.
Love. I don't know
whether you loved her
or whether you even liked her.
But I don't think that's
what any of this is about.
This play that you were in,
Lost in Time, who was cast first?
- You or Helaine?
- I don't really recall. I think she was.
She was. I confirmed
that with your director.
As a matter of fact, isn't that the
reason that you auditioned for the play
in the first place
because she was in it?
No. I didn't even
know who she was.
Are you saying that
you had never heard
of Helaine or Philip Cameron
prior to the day that you
auditioned for the play?
That's right.
I have a playbill from the
last play that you performed in.
I was looking over your credits.
Very impressive.
Thank you.
My goodness. Heh.
Mr. Drummond did Inherit
The Wind in Chicago.
He did Death of a
Salesman in Miami,
received rave reviews in a revival of
Cat on a Hot Tin Roof in Porterville.
He did...
Well, Mr. Drummond, did you know
that Helaine and Philip
Cameron were from Porterville?
Yes. I think she mentioned it.
- You killed her, didn't you?
- No, I did not.
Yes, you did.
And for the life of me, I
could not figure out why.
I mean, why would
you do such a thing?
Why would you date
a married woman,
over two months ago, take
out a life-insurance policy
in her husband's name to
frame him for the murder?
Do I have to listen to these
wild accusations, Your Honor?
Not if she doesn't have proof.
Miss Mclntyre?
I have proof, Your Honor.
- Proceed.
This play that you were doing in
Porterville, Cat on a Hot Tin Roof,
it had to close, didn't it?
Yes.
Would you tell the court why?
A few days into the play,
there was a car accident, and
one of the cast members died.
That would be the
actress who played Maggie.
Her name was Carla Waters.
Yes.
You were in love
with her, weren't you?
And Philip Cameron was
driving the car that hit her.
Okay. It's true. I was in
love with Carla Waters.
- Philip was responsible for her death.
- And so you decided to punish Philip.
You started dating
his wife. You killed her.
- Then you framed him for the murder.
- No.
Yes, I auditioned for the
play. Helaine was in it.
I fell in love with her. We
fell in love with each other.
Love is something that
is very difficult to control.
You didn't set out to
punish Philip Cameron?
No. I didn't set out to
punish or even hurt Philip.
On the night that
Helaine Cameron died,
you went over to her house
to rehearse, didn't you?
Yes.
How late did you
stay, Mr. Drummond?
I went home around 11.
Did you call anyone
when you got home?
- No.
- Did you see anyone?
No.
This is a copy of the play
that you and Helaine
Cameron were working on.
It was taken from
the scene of the crime.
I couldn't help but notice
that a lot of the dialogue in here
is highlighted in yellow marker.
Then an actor friend of mine
told me that actors do that.
The strange thing is is that
all of the dialogue highlighted
is for your character.
Is this your copy of the play?
Yes. As a matter of fact, it is.
When did you leave it
at Helaine Cameron's?
Well, I must have left it
there that night, I guess.
This is a copy of the play
taken this morning by
warrant from your house.
You'll notice that all
of the dialogue in here
that is highlighted
is for Helaine's role.
Well, I guess I
picked up her copy.
You'll also notice that on
page 14, there are blood stains
which the medical
examiner has identified
as Helaine Cameron's blood.
Oh, come on. You saw the
scene we had to do in that play.
So did your father. He
thought I was killing her.
I remember.
I had accidentally hit her in the
nose, and she got a nosebleed.
Not according to the medical
examiner who did the autopsy.
There was no blood
anywhere near Helaine's face,
no cuts on her body at all,
except for the wound that killed her.
So maybe it happened
the night before.
We rehearsed the
scene for a week.
I don't remember.
That's not possible either.
You see, as it turns out,
Helaine bought a new script
the morning that she died.
So the only way those blood
stains could have gotten on that script
was when you killed her.
Mr. Drummond, this was
a cold, murderous act.
You didn't kill out
of passion or hate.
In order to get back
at Philip Cameron,
you killed somebody
you didn't even dislike.
This was a cold-blooded,
premeditated
heartless assassination.
Five, five, six,
six, seven, seven,
eight, eight, nine,
nine, ten, ten.
Are you sure you
wanna play, Dad?
Do I hear a little
fear in your voice?
I feel bad when you lose.
Would 10-cent a point erase
some of that fear and bad feeling?
- Let's go.
- Okay.
Finally.
You're collecting fours.
Ah, I can use that seven.
Ah.
Oh.
You're playing
into my hand again.
Dad, remember Charlie
Haver from Mount Harlan?
Sure.
- What was it he used to drink?
- Gin.
Exactly.
www.tvsubtitles.net